<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>simon-sinek | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/simon-sinek/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/simon-sinek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>simon-sinek</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:48:07 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>simon-sinek</title>
      <link>/tag/simon-sinek/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Believe</title>
      <link>/post/why-believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:48:07 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/why-believe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the above statements from a marketing campaign. Try to differentiate between these two. The first one states three informative lines. First it tells that the company makes computers, agenda clear, then they tried to communicate that the computers they make are beautiful, and simple to use. Finally, they expose what their moto is that to sell and make profit. This is quite a fair way to communicate to your going to be customers but it’s not inspiring, it doesn’t feel ‘great’, you as a customer will not feel that enthusiasm in buying one. In other words, you’re trying to sell a windows computer (Example: only for understanding purposes, reality may be different, but I doubt it is not.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, now take a look at the second statement at the right. It tries to communicate almost the similar information, but the order of communication is reversed. Now, first we are telling our going to be consumers our belief. Why we make products, with this we are making so many things clear, people or the consumers are now ready to go ahead and read, they’re already in the similar universe that you are. Then we convey the information about how we make our believes concrete, i.e. by making beautifully designed, user friendly and simple to use products and finally we tell them, we happen to make great computers, why don’t you buy one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen a dirty Mac, no? Cause it doesn’t exist. We keep them shiny and clean because we believe what they believe. We love that shiny little apple logo on our computers. All that happen is because of the answer of ‘Why’. Getting it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really important to understand; it all starts with ‘why’. The chances of your succeeding in life or career depends a lot on the like-minded people you surround yourself with. The products you choose to have for yourself also depends on your belief on the product manufacturer. I gave the example of a Mac, because it’s easy to understand and we all know about apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek, a well-known motivational speaker and author, gave a rule for the same. He called it the golden circle rule. He mentioned that it’s really important to convey the right information in right manner. First, we should always convey the answer for all the whys, it makes couple of things clear to the audience. For example, why we’re here standing together, may be to talk about the things we all are excited about. Then we should try and answer hows. Now, that we have reasons to stand together, how we can make things more meaningful. Finally, we can picture the outcome, because that’s our end goal. This rule is pretty simple, but effective. We’ve already seen the example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever a company launches a new product, or you as a blogger starts writing about some topic, the very first consumer/audience is going to be the ones who also believe what you believe. Due to similar mind frame, people will be confident to choose your new products, instead of already available products or alternatives. And gives boost to your product or blog. It can make your initiative a success and I wish that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: Credit =&amp;gt; Simon Sinek for {enlightening us with the idea.}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
