<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/motivation/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>motivation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 18:57:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>motivation</title>
      <link>/tag/motivation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Morning Run Teaches You</title>
      <link>/post/what-a-morning-run-teaches-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 18:57:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/what-a-morning-run-teaches-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A morning run gives a perfect start to your day. It keeps you healthy and active. People are enjoying the freshness it provides. But a majority of population are not able to get out of their beds to make it a habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up early on Monday, went out, on track, ran, it felt like just now I started living. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to continue next day.
It happens, to a lot of them who give it a try. Getting out of bed, to run is easy to say but very hard when you have to. A morning run is a habit. But if you see it involves few more small but important habits. Your motive is single and simple, to feel active, that&amp;rsquo;s why you choose to run, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But a run is not. It has a pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To run you have to make a habit of waking up early, If you are able to do it a couple of days, it won&amp;rsquo;t take too long and you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself on track. It&amp;rsquo;s simple first start waking up early, don&amp;rsquo;t push yourself too much, just wake up (Second habit is to get out of bed, if you think getting out of bed a bit different than waking up). Now you are on track, start walking for a couple of days. Let yourself feel easy, you seem to enjoy it, freshness. Believe me you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself walking with ease in no time. And not too long from that day, you&amp;rsquo;ll start running. You can count running as your habit now, because it&amp;rsquo;s fulfilling your motive. You feel fresh, their was a day when you tried but failed, because it&amp;rsquo;s a habit, it takes time. So tried this pattern. A simpler but effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why this worked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ain&amp;rsquo;t magic, what you did is nothing but what you wanted. The key is to understand what&amp;rsquo;s stopping us from our goal. May be there are more than one reasons. Break them, check them one by one. Soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see your problem as a small one. One great thing about it is, when you try simplifying this, chances are more of you being into it, I mean succeeding. Like each time you took one step, chances were more of your doing the next. Yeah, you got it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it work in every aspect of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to work harder/smarter, get things done and smile, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Breaking and checking works in every aspect of life, ask yourself. Making a habit, breaking a habit(It&amp;rsquo;s a bad one!), Getting out of depression(might be a relationship or work pressure) for almost everything you can apply. I personally believe it&amp;rsquo;s a pattern, an effective one. So how you apply means a lot. Of course, habit of waking up is prior than, a walk. Simple get the idea, use your assets (Mind, I meant) and do it. I Hope, it&amp;rsquo;ll work out for you. Because a morning run gave us this lesson!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
