<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/motivation/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>motivation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 18:49:20 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>motivation</title>
      <link>/tag/motivation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Often</title>
      <link>/post/often/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 18:49:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/often/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you heard about this challenge #100DaysOfCode?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s more of an initiative, the core of which is repetition and social commitment. The idea that if you keep coding for &lt;code&gt;100&lt;/code&gt; days, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to learn a lot everyday. Atomically, one thing at a time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly I learned this while listening to James Clear&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;strong&gt;TheAtomicHabits&lt;/strong&gt;. He mentioned a story about this Professor at University of Florida, &lt;em&gt;Jerry Uelsmann&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The professor divided his photography class into two groups. He told the class that their grades depend on two different factors quantity and quality!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if that&amp;rsquo;s not interesting enough, he asked both the groups to focus on just one! For the first group, he asked them to click pictures and focus on quantity, take as many pictures as they can, cause their grades depend on it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second group, he asked them to focus on quality. To get an A, they have to click pictures of A grade quality!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess what happened at the end of term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quantity group produced not just more but also rather good pictures! It was surprising and also interesting to understand for the professor!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quantity group focused on taking a lot of photos. It gave them the luxury of experimenting with all sorts of factors! Lighting, scene and what not! They learned from their own mistakes. The process was fun for them and they learned the skill!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the quality group focused on speculation! e.g. what could make a picture the best! They had to sit and discuss about perfection!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since they had little to show and it had to be perfect! They (thought) couldn&amp;rsquo;t work on anything weak or average!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning is - its easy to loosen up if you focus on the perfect, and may be you&amp;rsquo;ll quit!
It&amp;rsquo;s always an iterative process. You learn while performing! The best is just another iteration in all of the other iterations you perform. It is just an event, which will happen, if you&amp;rsquo;re active!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on practicing more often!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://thriveglobal.com/stories/embracing-imperfection-achieving-goals/&#34;&gt;https://thriveglobal.com/stories/embracing-imperfection-achieving-goals/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.100daysofcode.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.100daysofcode.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atomic Habits Book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34;&gt;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Bold Bets</title>
      <link>/post/take-bold-bets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:46:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/take-bold-bets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take bold bets, that’s what they say!
When you try new things, take bold decisions, those are experiments. The thing about an experiment is that you don&amp;rsquo;t know ahead of time if they are gonna work. They are prone to failures. So you try! Try once, try again and again, but end up in failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the good thing about trying is that you might even end up with a Big Success! Or few big successes. That success compensates for dozens and dozens of Things that didn’t work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to embrace failure and fail forward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failures might drain you, make you feel dull and sad. But you need to find your harmony. For most people, it’s about meaning. People want to know that they are doing something interesting and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to be proud, not of your gifts, but your hard work and choices. You can be grateful for the gifts given to you. But it takes hard work to transform those gifts into success through hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be #Bold&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be #Proud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be #Modest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;courtesy ~ Jeff Bezos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed an Idea</title>
      <link>/post/seed-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 18:48:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/seed-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For next few minutes, set yourself free! Forget about all the dogmas! Forget about your age, you’re 23. You’re young and restless. You don’t have that exact thing how are you going to make an impact on the world, but you cannot settle for just anything. You are passionate, yeah! You know this word. Passion, you’re living it. Right now, in this very moment. It’s not over yet. It’s the year 1976! Yes, seventies, and yes you don’t have to care about your retro look by the way, just try keeping 70’s fashion away from your mind! Focus on your inner self, you’re passionate. This all is happening at this very moment. Finally, I need not mention arrogant. What more you want? Okay, you’ve just dropped out of your college, started looking at your friends? Who can play wozniak?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s 1976, you’re passionate about doing something amazing, everything around you is positive, you’re living the positive Steve jobs role. You’re all set, becoming Steve jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here it is, what am I looking at? The very next moment, you seem to lose that confidence, where’s that confident expression from your face? You’re losing it &amp;amp; bam! You’ve lost it. You can’t play Jobs anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story’s over! It got over at that very moment, when you started to feel negative. May be when you’d get the idea of dropping out of college is what made you negative, and you started losing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be you weren’t wrong, it happens. And that’s why Jobs was an exception. He was young, restless, passionate and sometimes arrogant too and yes he dropped out the college. But he did so because he didn’t find any value in it. He was firm with his decisions, and believed that it’ll all workout alright. He was confident, doesn’t mean that he wouldn’t have lost his confidence at times, but that was momentarily. He was able to continue doing whatever he wanted, because he blindly believed that he has control over his actions, and following your instincts can take you, where you truly want to go, but only actions can take you there. He was able to start &amp;amp; yes, in year 1976, he along with his geeky friend wozniak were able to produce apple I in July 1976 at a price of US$666.66. This was just the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, in an interview, he was asked about what made him so passionate about apple. His response was, “Once when I got a chance to visit a school, I saw a class with whole bunch of kids using apple tools for their studies, and that was fascinating in a way where very few people in case of apple II four, designed a computer &amp;amp; gave it to some other people who didn’t know how to design but they knew how to manufacture it on a large scale, then they gave it to some people who didn’t know how to design or manufacture but they knew how to distribute &amp;amp; then they gave it to people who knew how to write software for it &amp;amp; then came the consumers, who did magical things with this machine! It was a whole inverse pyramid that grew, which blossomed!” And yes, he was right, in fact he was right because everything came from an idea, a tiny little idea: seed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. This boring article is an excerpt from my not that boring book talk on Becoming Steve Jobs, given while I was working in TCS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decision to Make(yourself)</title>
      <link>/post/decision-to-make-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 18:49:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/decision-to-make-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is an interesting and exciting topic for research- why people do what they do. Studying on why and how people make decisions. Decisions as minor as which toothpaste to buy or decide to have children when the costs, in terms of money and hard work, can not be compared with the affection and contentment they bring. So hard to calculate. Talking about the Costs, Here in India, It can be seen that people are ready to send their Kids to expensive private schools instead of free public ones! Why does money is not a matter of fact here in Decision making. How do people decide to marry a person whom they know for few minutes and deny to those whom They know for Years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of our important decisions are, in fact, attempts to forecast the future. When people send their children to private expensive schools, it is in part, a bet that money spend today on schooling will yield happiness and opportunities in the future. When people decide to have a baby, they are in a way forecasting that the joy of becoming a parent will outweigh the cost of sleepless and tiring nights with the baby. When people choose to get married- though it may seem totally unromantic - They are, at some level, forecasting that the benefits of settling down are greater than the opportunity of seeing who else will come along on their journey. So These are in a way Decision Making, then what&amp;rsquo;s Good Decision Making?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Decision making is subject to the basic ability to envision what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how people managed, in course of their daily life choose various futures, without getting affected by the complexities of each choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why some people are able to make better Choices then others? Are they more skilled than others at envisioning various futures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think it&amp;rsquo;s a skill, It&amp;rsquo;s good that you&amp;rsquo;re predicting. Let&amp;rsquo;s make your day by affirming your words. Yes it&amp;rsquo;s a skill. It&amp;rsquo;s a Skill, where people who make it their comfort zone to remain in Doubt. How?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People by making decisions learn to live with doubt in their comfort zone.
It&amp;rsquo;s normal for people, to want to know how things will turn our. And it&amp;rsquo;s scary when we realize how much rides on choices where we can&amp;rsquo;t predict the future. Will the baby be born healthy or sick? Will my better half and I still love each other 5 years down the line? Does my kid will perform better if I invest more on him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forecasting is terrifying, science because it forces us to confront what we don&amp;rsquo;t know, even if we want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It expects us to live in a doubtful world and make comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a successful decision is precisely, to choose and to believe that it all work out Great
It&amp;rsquo;s a skill requiring to develop a comfort with doubt. You have to learn and develop this skill. Most of the successful people, entrepreneurs have done it. When they started their company. They had a vision, we know it was in a doubtful world, but that world was their comfort zone. Apple started in a Garage. Mr Jobs never would have imagined. But had a vision. He might have some doubts but that never stopped him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a successful decision is precisely, to choose and to believe that it all work out Great, with this doubt that(Even if it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, We&amp;rsquo;ll make it work Great!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do so, You&amp;rsquo;ll see yourself in your own Hall of Fame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Morning Run Teaches You</title>
      <link>/post/what-a-morning-run-teaches-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 18:57:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/what-a-morning-run-teaches-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A morning run gives a perfect start to your day. It keeps you healthy and active. People are enjoying the freshness it provides. But a majority of population are not able to get out of their beds to make it a habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up early on Monday, went out, on track, ran, it felt like just now I started living. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to continue next day.
It happens, to a lot of them who give it a try. Getting out of bed, to run is easy to say but very hard when you have to. A morning run is a habit. But if you see it involves few more small but important habits. Your motive is single and simple, to feel active, that&amp;rsquo;s why you choose to run, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But a run is not. It has a pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To run you have to make a habit of waking up early, If you are able to do it a couple of days, it won&amp;rsquo;t take too long and you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself on track. It&amp;rsquo;s simple first start waking up early, don&amp;rsquo;t push yourself too much, just wake up (Second habit is to get out of bed, if you think getting out of bed a bit different than waking up). Now you are on track, start walking for a couple of days. Let yourself feel easy, you seem to enjoy it, freshness. Believe me you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself walking with ease in no time. And not too long from that day, you&amp;rsquo;ll start running. You can count running as your habit now, because it&amp;rsquo;s fulfilling your motive. You feel fresh, their was a day when you tried but failed, because it&amp;rsquo;s a habit, it takes time. So tried this pattern. A simpler but effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why this worked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ain&amp;rsquo;t magic, what you did is nothing but what you wanted. The key is to understand what&amp;rsquo;s stopping us from our goal. May be there are more than one reasons. Break them, check them one by one. Soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see your problem as a small one. One great thing about it is, when you try simplifying this, chances are more of you being into it, I mean succeeding. Like each time you took one step, chances were more of your doing the next. Yeah, you got it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it work in every aspect of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to work harder/smarter, get things done and smile, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Breaking and checking works in every aspect of life, ask yourself. Making a habit, breaking a habit(It&amp;rsquo;s a bad one!), Getting out of depression(might be a relationship or work pressure) for almost everything you can apply. I personally believe it&amp;rsquo;s a pattern, an effective one. So how you apply means a lot. Of course, habit of waking up is prior than, a walk. Simple get the idea, use your assets (Mind, I meant) and do it. I Hope, it&amp;rsquo;ll work out for you. Because a morning run gave us this lesson!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
