<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>behaviour | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/behaviour/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/behaviour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>behaviour</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 18:47:15 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>behaviour</title>
      <link>/tag/behaviour/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urge - Stay away from it</title>
      <link>/post/urge-stay-away-from-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 18:47:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/urge-stay-away-from-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive workout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are encouraged to ask for help in difficult times. Times when we&amp;rsquo;ve tried a number of approaches and those didn&amp;rsquo;t work out, we are stuck and it&amp;rsquo;s probably the best time to reach out to someone and ask for support. In my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s a good tactic, but only when we&amp;rsquo;re sure we&amp;rsquo;ve made enough cognitive progress. Cognitive progress means that, you know why it ain&amp;rsquo;t working out for you. It means that you have given sufficient time to the problem and tried to acquire some knowledge in regards to the problem domain. Eventually, we tend to reach out to people whom we expect to help ourselves. But it&amp;rsquo;s incongruent to our own belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Leaky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times when we don&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge of reaching out to someone, we get the solution, good. But the process of reaching out to a conclusion, or let&amp;rsquo;s say getting a problem&amp;rsquo;s solution we miss the process, the process which involves those few non-working but essential points we should have known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All we know is the steps. Aha, what&amp;rsquo;s the difference? Process, steps, steps process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the steps to solve a problem can be a sequence of actions. It&amp;rsquo;s more of an answer to &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo;. But the important thing is to know the process, it&amp;rsquo;s an answer to &amp;ldquo;why and then what is&amp;rdquo;. So when you reach out to someone without any preparation, or let&amp;rsquo;s say work, you don&amp;rsquo;t get the whole process. What you get is some steps and that&amp;rsquo;s why the information is leaky. It leaks out essential gems of the process of problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burning the boats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like if you&amp;rsquo;ve to cross a river, and you have a boat, you tend to use the boat to cross it. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s simple, because this thought of owning a boat is stick to your mind. Whenever you have to cross, you use the boat. But what you should do is to build a bridge to get to the other end. Building a bridge takes time, it takes patience, but the result is weigh more impactful. You agree to me, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing to build the bridge? The first and foremost action, you should take is to burn the boat. You have to get rid of this urge of reaching out to someone. You have to be on your own. Yes, of course, it&amp;rsquo;s hard, it&amp;rsquo;s going to take time, but the result is worth the efforts. What you gain is permanent. Burning the boat gives you two things. First, you won&amp;rsquo;t have a second thought of using the boat when your patience runs out. Second, you&amp;rsquo;ll be sure about the importance of building the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we have to be hard to ourselves, we have to make extra efforts and believe me the cost of efforts are worth the gain of outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions</title>
      <link>/post/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 18:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you kidding me? No, but a note at the beginning, there’s going to be a lot of questions in this post. Let’s see if you enjoy it. What do you think? Do we need a definition of what a question is? Nah! We don’t need to have a number of certain words, if put together in a structured manner, making some meaning we already know, do we? Anyway, let me tell you there are two categories of questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One that make sense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, stop and guess which one is the second? Yeah, those which do not fall in the first category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, which are not in first category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And mark my words, I did not say, few questions do not make any sense. Don’t assume it. Don’t believe me? Wait! Take a look at this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Rank the candidates in order of how bad they were in the interview. Worst takes precedence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;___ David

___ Cristiano

___ Leonardo

___ Serena

___ Chuck Norris
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you like the question? Is this a category one or a category two question? Well, I’ll leave that to you, comments are welcome. But, one thing for sure, the one who asked this question, seemed to me as going through something in life and this is not saying that candidates were not good. Or May be it’s a test for the interviewer, god knows. Let’s take a look at another question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Did you watch the movie, Dunkirk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, which category does this question falls into? May be the first one, if you’ve something with which you can follow up, then it makes sense to ask questions such as these, or else you know, if you don’t care about the answer, then it’s a sign that boss you’ve got problems! or you’re an introvert. Okay, my turn, one of my favorite questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. What is the meaning of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ___ (Do we need this?)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are called rhetorical questions. Okay, so did we just give a third classification? No, obviously not, this question does not make any sense, where’s the bucket for category two questions? Few more of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Why me? (Asked under some serious circumstances)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. (Girl to her Boy) How much you love me? (ha ha ha)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one definitely gives the boy some hard time. Well, questions are not always asked to make sense. A lot of times these are asked as answers to themselves. Of course, “Why me?” is of that sort. But why do we bother about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of making sense, questions are there. If you have some, then ask. By the way, why did we choose this picture(Look atop) for our post?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no point asking that, is there?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
