<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psychology | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/psychology/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>psychology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 18:27:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>psychology</title>
      <link>/tag/psychology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting to Be Identified</title>
      <link>/post/waiting-to-be-identified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 18:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/waiting-to-be-identified/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s an old joke – How do you know someone’s a Vegetarian?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Punch line to this is - Don’t worry, they will tell you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a vegetarian, I have lived this Joke. Moreover, telling people that I’m a vegetarian, clarifies that I don’t eat meat. This is just to identify myself, telling others of my choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Identity, is much more powerful than this. The way we see ourselves, has a profound impact on how we deal with traction and distractions. Our perception about selves can largely impact our actions in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Bryan, along with his fellow psychology researchers from Stanford designed a study around this thing called Identity. The study was performed to test how thinking about ourselves can affect our actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He performed this study among two groups of voters. They were given a task to complete questions related to an upcoming election. Questions asked to one group included a verb to vote, for example &amp;ldquo;How important is it for you to vote?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second group answered similar questions included the noun Voter, instead of the verb, like &amp;ldquo;How important is it for you to be a Voter?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers cross referenced voting records to confirm whether they have actually voted. The results showed that a minor difference in words proved to make a big difference. It showed that being a voter were much more likely to vote than those who were asked how likely they were to vote!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going beyond to ensure the results were correct, researchers conducted another election to confirm the validity, but the results were the same. The Voter group dramatically outperformed the to vote group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results concluded that individuals are more likely to act when that act is represented as an expression of them, like their personal self, character or behavior, in other words their Identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nir Eyal, in his book Indistractable writes, “Identity is another cognitive shortcut that helps our brain make otherwise difficult choices in advance, thereby streamlining decision making. Our perception of who we are changes what we do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By thinking of yourself as a person with identity, YOU empower yourself and YOU trigger your actions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use this Identity as a rationale to tell others why you do what you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use it wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;courtesy ~ Nir Eyal | From the Book InDistractable&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decision to Make(yourself)</title>
      <link>/post/decision-to-make-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 18:49:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/decision-to-make-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is an interesting and exciting topic for research- why people do what they do. Studying on why and how people make decisions. Decisions as minor as which toothpaste to buy or decide to have children when the costs, in terms of money and hard work, can not be compared with the affection and contentment they bring. So hard to calculate. Talking about the Costs, Here in India, It can be seen that people are ready to send their Kids to expensive private schools instead of free public ones! Why does money is not a matter of fact here in Decision making. How do people decide to marry a person whom they know for few minutes and deny to those whom They know for Years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of our important decisions are, in fact, attempts to forecast the future. When people send their children to private expensive schools, it is in part, a bet that money spend today on schooling will yield happiness and opportunities in the future. When people decide to have a baby, they are in a way forecasting that the joy of becoming a parent will outweigh the cost of sleepless and tiring nights with the baby. When people choose to get married- though it may seem totally unromantic - They are, at some level, forecasting that the benefits of settling down are greater than the opportunity of seeing who else will come along on their journey. So These are in a way Decision Making, then what&amp;rsquo;s Good Decision Making?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Decision making is subject to the basic ability to envision what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how people managed, in course of their daily life choose various futures, without getting affected by the complexities of each choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why some people are able to make better Choices then others? Are they more skilled than others at envisioning various futures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think it&amp;rsquo;s a skill, It&amp;rsquo;s good that you&amp;rsquo;re predicting. Let&amp;rsquo;s make your day by affirming your words. Yes it&amp;rsquo;s a skill. It&amp;rsquo;s a Skill, where people who make it their comfort zone to remain in Doubt. How?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People by making decisions learn to live with doubt in their comfort zone.
It&amp;rsquo;s normal for people, to want to know how things will turn our. And it&amp;rsquo;s scary when we realize how much rides on choices where we can&amp;rsquo;t predict the future. Will the baby be born healthy or sick? Will my better half and I still love each other 5 years down the line? Does my kid will perform better if I invest more on him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forecasting is terrifying, science because it forces us to confront what we don&amp;rsquo;t know, even if we want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It expects us to live in a doubtful world and make comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a successful decision is precisely, to choose and to believe that it all work out Great
It&amp;rsquo;s a skill requiring to develop a comfort with doubt. You have to learn and develop this skill. Most of the successful people, entrepreneurs have done it. When they started their company. They had a vision, we know it was in a doubtful world, but that world was their comfort zone. Apple started in a Garage. Mr Jobs never would have imagined. But had a vision. He might have some doubts but that never stopped him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a successful decision is precisely, to choose and to believe that it all work out Great, with this doubt that(Even if it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, We&amp;rsquo;ll make it work Great!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do so, You&amp;rsquo;ll see yourself in your own Hall of Fame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
