<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:48:07 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Believe</title>
      <link>/post/why-believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:48:07 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/why-believe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the above statements from a marketing campaign. Try to differentiate between these two. The first one states three informative lines. First it tells that the company makes computers, agenda clear, then they tried to communicate that the computers they make are beautiful, and simple to use. Finally, they expose what their moto is that to sell and make profit. This is quite a fair way to communicate to your going to be customers but it’s not inspiring, it doesn’t feel ‘great’, you as a customer will not feel that enthusiasm in buying one. In other words, you’re trying to sell a windows computer (Example: only for understanding purposes, reality may be different, but I doubt it is not.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, now take a look at the second statement at the right. It tries to communicate almost the similar information, but the order of communication is reversed. Now, first we are telling our going to be consumers our belief. Why we make products, with this we are making so many things clear, people or the consumers are now ready to go ahead and read, they’re already in the similar universe that you are. Then we convey the information about how we make our believes concrete, i.e. by making beautifully designed, user friendly and simple to use products and finally we tell them, we happen to make great computers, why don’t you buy one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen a dirty Mac, no? Cause it doesn’t exist. We keep them shiny and clean because we believe what they believe. We love that shiny little apple logo on our computers. All that happen is because of the answer of ‘Why’. Getting it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really important to understand; it all starts with ‘why’. The chances of your succeeding in life or career depends a lot on the like-minded people you surround yourself with. The products you choose to have for yourself also depends on your belief on the product manufacturer. I gave the example of a Mac, because it’s easy to understand and we all know about apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek, a well-known motivational speaker and author, gave a rule for the same. He called it the golden circle rule. He mentioned that it’s really important to convey the right information in right manner. First, we should always convey the answer for all the whys, it makes couple of things clear to the audience. For example, why we’re here standing together, may be to talk about the things we all are excited about. Then we should try and answer hows. Now, that we have reasons to stand together, how we can make things more meaningful. Finally, we can picture the outcome, because that’s our end goal. This rule is pretty simple, but effective. We’ve already seen the example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever a company launches a new product, or you as a blogger starts writing about some topic, the very first consumer/audience is going to be the ones who also believe what you believe. Due to similar mind frame, people will be confident to choose your new products, instead of already available products or alternatives. And gives boost to your product or blog. It can make your initiative a success and I wish that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: Credit =&amp;gt; Simon Sinek for {enlightening us with the idea.}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting to Be Identified</title>
      <link>/post/waiting-to-be-identified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 18:27:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/waiting-to-be-identified/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s an old joke – How do you know someone’s a Vegetarian?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Punch line to this is - Don’t worry, they will tell you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a vegetarian, I have lived this Joke. Moreover, telling people that I’m a vegetarian, clarifies that I don’t eat meat. This is just to identify myself, telling others of my choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Identity, is much more powerful than this. The way we see ourselves, has a profound impact on how we deal with traction and distractions. Our perception about selves can largely impact our actions in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Bryan, along with his fellow psychology researchers from Stanford designed a study around this thing called Identity. The study was performed to test how thinking about ourselves can affect our actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He performed this study among two groups of voters. They were given a task to complete questions related to an upcoming election. Questions asked to one group included a verb to vote, for example &amp;ldquo;How important is it for you to vote?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second group answered similar questions included the noun Voter, instead of the verb, like &amp;ldquo;How important is it for you to be a Voter?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers cross referenced voting records to confirm whether they have actually voted. The results showed that a minor difference in words proved to make a big difference. It showed that being a voter were much more likely to vote than those who were asked how likely they were to vote!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going beyond to ensure the results were correct, researchers conducted another election to confirm the validity, but the results were the same. The Voter group dramatically outperformed the to vote group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results concluded that individuals are more likely to act when that act is represented as an expression of them, like their personal self, character or behavior, in other words their Identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nir Eyal, in his book Indistractable writes, “Identity is another cognitive shortcut that helps our brain make otherwise difficult choices in advance, thereby streamlining decision making. Our perception of who we are changes what we do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By thinking of yourself as a person with identity, YOU empower yourself and YOU trigger your actions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use this Identity as a rationale to tell others why you do what you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use it wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;courtesy ~ Nir Eyal | From the Book InDistractable&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Bold Bets</title>
      <link>/post/take-bold-bets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:46:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/take-bold-bets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take bold bets, that’s what they say!
When you try new things, take bold decisions, those are experiments. The thing about an experiment is that you don&amp;rsquo;t know ahead of time if they are gonna work. They are prone to failures. So you try! Try once, try again and again, but end up in failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the good thing about trying is that you might even end up with a Big Success! Or few big successes. That success compensates for dozens and dozens of Things that didn’t work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to embrace failure and fail forward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failures might drain you, make you feel dull and sad. But you need to find your harmony. For most people, it’s about meaning. People want to know that they are doing something interesting and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to be proud, not of your gifts, but your hard work and choices. You can be grateful for the gifts given to you. But it takes hard work to transform those gifts into success through hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be #Bold&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be #Proud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be #Modest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;courtesy ~ Jeff Bezos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urge - Stay away from it</title>
      <link>/post/urge-stay-away-from-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 18:47:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/urge-stay-away-from-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive workout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are encouraged to ask for help in difficult times. Times when we&amp;rsquo;ve tried a number of approaches and those didn&amp;rsquo;t work out, we are stuck and it&amp;rsquo;s probably the best time to reach out to someone and ask for support. In my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s a good tactic, but only when we&amp;rsquo;re sure we&amp;rsquo;ve made enough cognitive progress. Cognitive progress means that, you know why it ain&amp;rsquo;t working out for you. It means that you have given sufficient time to the problem and tried to acquire some knowledge in regards to the problem domain. Eventually, we tend to reach out to people whom we expect to help ourselves. But it&amp;rsquo;s incongruent to our own belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Leaky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times when we don&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge of reaching out to someone, we get the solution, good. But the process of reaching out to a conclusion, or let&amp;rsquo;s say getting a problem&amp;rsquo;s solution we miss the process, the process which involves those few non-working but essential points we should have known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All we know is the steps. Aha, what&amp;rsquo;s the difference? Process, steps, steps process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the steps to solve a problem can be a sequence of actions. It&amp;rsquo;s more of an answer to &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo;. But the important thing is to know the process, it&amp;rsquo;s an answer to &amp;ldquo;why and then what is&amp;rdquo;. So when you reach out to someone without any preparation, or let&amp;rsquo;s say work, you don&amp;rsquo;t get the whole process. What you get is some steps and that&amp;rsquo;s why the information is leaky. It leaks out essential gems of the process of problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burning the boats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like if you&amp;rsquo;ve to cross a river, and you have a boat, you tend to use the boat to cross it. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s simple, because this thought of owning a boat is stick to your mind. Whenever you have to cross, you use the boat. But what you should do is to build a bridge to get to the other end. Building a bridge takes time, it takes patience, but the result is weigh more impactful. You agree to me, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing to build the bridge? The first and foremost action, you should take is to burn the boat. You have to get rid of this urge of reaching out to someone. You have to be on your own. Yes, of course, it&amp;rsquo;s hard, it&amp;rsquo;s going to take time, but the result is worth the efforts. What you gain is permanent. Burning the boat gives you two things. First, you won&amp;rsquo;t have a second thought of using the boat when your patience runs out. Second, you&amp;rsquo;ll be sure about the importance of building the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we have to be hard to ourselves, we have to make extra efforts and believe me the cost of efforts are worth the gain of outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear: Sister of an Excuse</title>
      <link>/post/fear-sister-of-an-excuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 18:47:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/fear-sister-of-an-excuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It felt so good, when I noticed two things I was very good at. First was giving up and second was the fear of doing things. And then a sudden wink (a not that creepy one), I thought why not combine these two. I gave up on fear of doing the things I wanted. May be that’s why I’m writing funny and boring stuff today. And really, this so called fear is stopping a majority of gentlemen and ladies from what they really want to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a coincidence but I know a guy, who once worked as a salesman. His job was to visit houses door to door and sell stuff, the kind of stuff people restrain to buy. And he was so confident with his fear that he will never be able to make it through. How can you sell stuff, if even you’re not confident about it? He was so used to the negative response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was stunned recently to see a big change in him. I was eager to know what exactly changed him and his answer really changed my perspective (may be because I was able to see the results). His exact words were “I kept trying to sell the stuff, and when I got my first customer, there was no going back. It was me who was wrong and not the product. Once I believed that it works, I was able to sell.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to keep doing it. And when you break through it, it really becomes a game for you. Fear shouldn’t be a reason, why you’re not able to achieve something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure death can make it to the top five reasons to fear. And we all know smoking cigarettes kill people. Yet study shows that 70% of people who know this deep inside their heart do not stop smoking. Jokes apart, but I believe fear is nothing but an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the times, we act like this gentleman up against the wall on the right and do something when there’s nowhere to go. But in that we lose the flexibility to plan upfront and deliver well. It’s now obvious that we’ve have to practice so that we don’t use fear as an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a need of deliberate practice, not just physical practice, but mental practice. If you’ve something in your mind that’s not letting you try out things that you want to, it’s your duty to find a way or if it does not exist, make a way and then put massive action to accomplish. If you really think fear is even a word, then you use it your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A famous writer, wrote in his book, if an emotional hook named fear is stopping you to try out your stuff, take yourself out of the motion picture of your life and imagine you’re watching yourself in the frame. Now, think like an 8-year-old, free yourself from “what others may think of me”, “what if they don’t like my work” or “What if I fail” and remember Nike’s slogan (not too much for an 8-year-old, right?), just do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time try at least once, before you talk yourself out. And come ‘on give up on Fear!
End title: Another boring post[five]: Fear {lol, don&amp;rsquo;t buy it!}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Planting vs Growing a Tree</title>
      <link>/post/results-planting-vs-growing-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 18:47:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/results-planting-vs-growing-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you have a garden? Oh, you love watering the trees, great! If you have, maybe you have tried planting a seed. That’s fantastic, if not let’s try something, plant a seed, water it and go home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning, it’s a new day, go check out the seed, has it grown? No? Ok, no worries, just water it, we’ll come back tomorrow. Do this for a couple of days, go and check each day, is it not growing as expected, you were only able to see tiny leaves, no flowers yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, stop it man! We know it takes time. It doesn’t grow this soon. It takes time, cause it’s natural. Oh, then it’s time for you to understand, that’s how we should treat ourselves. We are also not machines, we are a natural product (Yes, really). Whenever you start learning anything, you know that the first day is like planting a seed, then you can’t get away, you’ve to water it for its growth. At the same time, it’s important to keep your patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that it takes time. It’s really idiotic to expect some result every day, but it’s important to make an effort for the result. There are times, when we pressure ourselves so hard, we forget that it’s a natural phenomenon that whatever time we’re investing, is worth and of real importance for us to grow. Every tiny bit you’re learning every day is of so much importance. Results are like flowers (or fruits if you’d like) so you have to wait for them to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, said this, it’s obvious (you must) for you to know about the flowers. If you have no idea about why you’re planting the seed. Then even if it’s good to plant a seed, you may not be watering it and that’ll in effect destroy (don’t do) it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know your reasons, even if it’s based on future outcomes. Knowing them, will make you put your efforts every day. It’s called perseverance, quoting Wikipedia for it, your actions despite the difficulty or delay in achieving success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ve just got to know an already known fact about yourself (your actions).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed an Idea</title>
      <link>/post/seed-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 18:48:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/seed-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For next few minutes, set yourself free! Forget about all the dogmas! Forget about your age, you’re 23. You’re young and restless. You don’t have that exact thing how are you going to make an impact on the world, but you cannot settle for just anything. You are passionate, yeah! You know this word. Passion, you’re living it. Right now, in this very moment. It’s not over yet. It’s the year 1976! Yes, seventies, and yes you don’t have to care about your retro look by the way, just try keeping 70’s fashion away from your mind! Focus on your inner self, you’re passionate. This all is happening at this very moment. Finally, I need not mention arrogant. What more you want? Okay, you’ve just dropped out of your college, started looking at your friends? Who can play wozniak?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s 1976, you’re passionate about doing something amazing, everything around you is positive, you’re living the positive Steve jobs role. You’re all set, becoming Steve jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here it is, what am I looking at? The very next moment, you seem to lose that confidence, where’s that confident expression from your face? You’re losing it &amp;amp; bam! You’ve lost it. You can’t play Jobs anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story’s over! It got over at that very moment, when you started to feel negative. May be when you’d get the idea of dropping out of college is what made you negative, and you started losing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be you weren’t wrong, it happens. And that’s why Jobs was an exception. He was young, restless, passionate and sometimes arrogant too and yes he dropped out the college. But he did so because he didn’t find any value in it. He was firm with his decisions, and believed that it’ll all workout alright. He was confident, doesn’t mean that he wouldn’t have lost his confidence at times, but that was momentarily. He was able to continue doing whatever he wanted, because he blindly believed that he has control over his actions, and following your instincts can take you, where you truly want to go, but only actions can take you there. He was able to start &amp;amp; yes, in year 1976, he along with his geeky friend wozniak were able to produce apple I in July 1976 at a price of US$666.66. This was just the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, in an interview, he was asked about what made him so passionate about apple. His response was, “Once when I got a chance to visit a school, I saw a class with whole bunch of kids using apple tools for their studies, and that was fascinating in a way where very few people in case of apple II four, designed a computer &amp;amp; gave it to some other people who didn’t know how to design but they knew how to manufacture it on a large scale, then they gave it to some people who didn’t know how to design or manufacture but they knew how to distribute &amp;amp; then they gave it to people who knew how to write software for it &amp;amp; then came the consumers, who did magical things with this machine! It was a whole inverse pyramid that grew, which blossomed!” And yes, he was right, in fact he was right because everything came from an idea, a tiny little idea: seed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. This boring article is an excerpt from my not that boring book talk on Becoming Steve Jobs, given while I was working in TCS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions</title>
      <link>/post/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 18:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you kidding me? No, but a note at the beginning, there’s going to be a lot of questions in this post. Let’s see if you enjoy it. What do you think? Do we need a definition of what a question is? Nah! We don’t need to have a number of certain words, if put together in a structured manner, making some meaning we already know, do we? Anyway, let me tell you there are two categories of questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One that make sense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, stop and guess which one is the second? Yeah, those which do not fall in the first category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, which are not in first category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And mark my words, I did not say, few questions do not make any sense. Don’t assume it. Don’t believe me? Wait! Take a look at this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Rank the candidates in order of how bad they were in the interview. Worst takes precedence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;___ David

___ Cristiano

___ Leonardo

___ Serena

___ Chuck Norris
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you like the question? Is this a category one or a category two question? Well, I’ll leave that to you, comments are welcome. But, one thing for sure, the one who asked this question, seemed to me as going through something in life and this is not saying that candidates were not good. Or May be it’s a test for the interviewer, god knows. Let’s take a look at another question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Did you watch the movie, Dunkirk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, which category does this question falls into? May be the first one, if you’ve something with which you can follow up, then it makes sense to ask questions such as these, or else you know, if you don’t care about the answer, then it’s a sign that boss you’ve got problems! or you’re an introvert. Okay, my turn, one of my favorite questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. What is the meaning of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ___ (Do we need this?)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are called rhetorical questions. Okay, so did we just give a third classification? No, obviously not, this question does not make any sense, where’s the bucket for category two questions? Few more of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Why me? (Asked under some serious circumstances)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. (Girl to her Boy) How much you love me? (ha ha ha)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one definitely gives the boy some hard time. Well, questions are not always asked to make sense. A lot of times these are asked as answers to themselves. Of course, “Why me?” is of that sort. But why do we bother about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of making sense, questions are there. If you have some, then ask. By the way, why did we choose this picture(Look atop) for our post?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no point asking that, is there?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems Everyone Have Their Own</title>
      <link>/post/problems-everyone-have-their-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 18:48:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/problems-everyone-have-their-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ For Every complex problem, there is an answer that is clear, simple and wrong.”
~ H.L. Mencken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our world, there is something, every human being has confronted. What’s that? A Problem. To be precise ‘Problems’, cause there’s not just one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day (It wasn’t raining!), I tried to be decisive. I decided that I would follow my instincts. I would listen to my inner voice. I moved forward to keep my point against someone I admire. I’d to deal with my emotions. I knew I possibly could. I was lacking with my ability to think clearly and was afraid that I would show some idiosyncratic behaviour. I knew what my problem was, but really didn’t have any idea, what could be the solution. But I pitched!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t recollect the source of this, may be some studies done on problems. Their origins and outcomes or so. Problems have been categorized to majorly three different categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple Problems
Complicated Problems
Complex Problems
Simple Problems are real simple problems. We can solve them following some particular method or set of steps. For examples Riding a Bike, making a cup of tea, baking your favourite cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these come under simple problems. To solve you don’t have to go deep, no need of brainstorming. With some steps to follow, you’re able to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then comes complicated problems. Complicated problems are hard, but can be broken down further to solve. For example, putting a satellite into orbit. Sending a human being on a space mission. All these are example of complicated problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some real good science knowledge, may be astrophysics and some billionaire sponsor you can achieve your target. So complicated problems can be broken down further to simple problems and each can be solved on their own. And Woah! You solved a complicated, impossible looking problem. You know Everything is hard, before its easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third category is complex problems. Not sure If these are hard, but surely serious problems! Can you see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about this. Raising a kid is an example of a complex problem. There’s no solution cookbook. No defined steps for that. Every kid is different in his/her own way. It’s impossible to treat everyone the same way. That’s complex isn’t it? Then what’s the way to solve these life problems? Is there any hack to these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be that day wasn’t a great day. I wanted an answer but that was not the solution to my problem. Well neither got the answer (expected) nor the solution. Came back home, I thought about it. I was able to convince myself that I need time and It’ll be okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that it? over? Really? No!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution to Complex problems can’t be that easy. If I don’t know what are the steps, how am I supposed to solve a problem. Then comes the saviour with a life hack. That is time. In my experience there’s some mathematics going on in the background, may be that looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hack to complex problem = time / (efforts \* (patience + believe))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more efforts you put, more the chances of feeling less complexity. If you put zero efforts or don’t show any patience or believe, then, guess what? Complexity can be infinity. As it happened in my case. Then there is time. If somehow you put good amount of efforts and patience, you believe that It’ll be okay, then It’s the moment you’ve hacked your problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And If you’re really good at maths and think, what If we put time = 0. Problem will be zero. Then you’re absolutely right. It’ll be zero. But that’s called a straight life line. We’ve a quote for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is the solution to all Problems. No man – no Problems. ~ Joseph Stalin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decision to Make(yourself)</title>
      <link>/post/decision-to-make-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 18:49:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/decision-to-make-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is an interesting and exciting topic for research- why people do what they do. Studying on why and how people make decisions. Decisions as minor as which toothpaste to buy or decide to have children when the costs, in terms of money and hard work, can not be compared with the affection and contentment they bring. So hard to calculate. Talking about the Costs, Here in India, It can be seen that people are ready to send their Kids to expensive private schools instead of free public ones! Why does money is not a matter of fact here in Decision making. How do people decide to marry a person whom they know for few minutes and deny to those whom They know for Years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of our important decisions are, in fact, attempts to forecast the future. When people send their children to private expensive schools, it is in part, a bet that money spend today on schooling will yield happiness and opportunities in the future. When people decide to have a baby, they are in a way forecasting that the joy of becoming a parent will outweigh the cost of sleepless and tiring nights with the baby. When people choose to get married- though it may seem totally unromantic - They are, at some level, forecasting that the benefits of settling down are greater than the opportunity of seeing who else will come along on their journey. So These are in a way Decision Making, then what&amp;rsquo;s Good Decision Making?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Decision making is subject to the basic ability to envision what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how people managed, in course of their daily life choose various futures, without getting affected by the complexities of each choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why some people are able to make better Choices then others? Are they more skilled than others at envisioning various futures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think it&amp;rsquo;s a skill, It&amp;rsquo;s good that you&amp;rsquo;re predicting. Let&amp;rsquo;s make your day by affirming your words. Yes it&amp;rsquo;s a skill. It&amp;rsquo;s a Skill, where people who make it their comfort zone to remain in Doubt. How?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People by making decisions learn to live with doubt in their comfort zone.
It&amp;rsquo;s normal for people, to want to know how things will turn our. And it&amp;rsquo;s scary when we realize how much rides on choices where we can&amp;rsquo;t predict the future. Will the baby be born healthy or sick? Will my better half and I still love each other 5 years down the line? Does my kid will perform better if I invest more on him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forecasting is terrifying, science because it forces us to confront what we don&amp;rsquo;t know, even if we want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It expects us to live in a doubtful world and make comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a successful decision is precisely, to choose and to believe that it all work out Great
It&amp;rsquo;s a skill requiring to develop a comfort with doubt. You have to learn and develop this skill. Most of the successful people, entrepreneurs have done it. When they started their company. They had a vision, we know it was in a doubtful world, but that world was their comfort zone. Apple started in a Garage. Mr Jobs never would have imagined. But had a vision. He might have some doubts but that never stopped him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a successful decision is precisely, to choose and to believe that it all work out Great, with this doubt that(Even if it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, We&amp;rsquo;ll make it work Great!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do so, You&amp;rsquo;ll see yourself in your own Hall of Fame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Morning Run Teaches You</title>
      <link>/post/what-a-morning-run-teaches-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 18:57:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/what-a-morning-run-teaches-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A morning run gives a perfect start to your day. It keeps you healthy and active. People are enjoying the freshness it provides. But a majority of population are not able to get out of their beds to make it a habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up early on Monday, went out, on track, ran, it felt like just now I started living. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to continue next day.
It happens, to a lot of them who give it a try. Getting out of bed, to run is easy to say but very hard when you have to. A morning run is a habit. But if you see it involves few more small but important habits. Your motive is single and simple, to feel active, that&amp;rsquo;s why you choose to run, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But a run is not. It has a pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To run you have to make a habit of waking up early, If you are able to do it a couple of days, it won&amp;rsquo;t take too long and you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself on track. It&amp;rsquo;s simple first start waking up early, don&amp;rsquo;t push yourself too much, just wake up (Second habit is to get out of bed, if you think getting out of bed a bit different than waking up). Now you are on track, start walking for a couple of days. Let yourself feel easy, you seem to enjoy it, freshness. Believe me you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself walking with ease in no time. And not too long from that day, you&amp;rsquo;ll start running. You can count running as your habit now, because it&amp;rsquo;s fulfilling your motive. You feel fresh, their was a day when you tried but failed, because it&amp;rsquo;s a habit, it takes time. So tried this pattern. A simpler but effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why this worked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ain&amp;rsquo;t magic, what you did is nothing but what you wanted. The key is to understand what&amp;rsquo;s stopping us from our goal. May be there are more than one reasons. Break them, check them one by one. Soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see your problem as a small one. One great thing about it is, when you try simplifying this, chances are more of you being into it, I mean succeeding. Like each time you took one step, chances were more of your doing the next. Yeah, you got it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it work in every aspect of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to work harder/smarter, get things done and smile, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Breaking and checking works in every aspect of life, ask yourself. Making a habit, breaking a habit(It&amp;rsquo;s a bad one!), Getting out of depression(might be a relationship or work pressure) for almost everything you can apply. I personally believe it&amp;rsquo;s a pattern, an effective one. So how you apply means a lot. Of course, habit of waking up is prior than, a walk. Simple get the idea, use your assets (Mind, I meant) and do it. I Hope, it&amp;rsquo;ll work out for you. Because a morning run gave us this lesson!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
