<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/self/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>self</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 18:48:59 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>self</title>
      <link>/tag/self/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems Everyone Have Their Own</title>
      <link>/post/problems-everyone-have-their-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 18:48:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/problems-everyone-have-their-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ For Every complex problem, there is an answer that is clear, simple and wrong.”
~ H.L. Mencken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our world, there is something, every human being has confronted. What’s that? A Problem. To be precise ‘Problems’, cause there’s not just one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day (It wasn’t raining!), I tried to be decisive. I decided that I would follow my instincts. I would listen to my inner voice. I moved forward to keep my point against someone I admire. I’d to deal with my emotions. I knew I possibly could. I was lacking with my ability to think clearly and was afraid that I would show some idiosyncratic behaviour. I knew what my problem was, but really didn’t have any idea, what could be the solution. But I pitched!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t recollect the source of this, may be some studies done on problems. Their origins and outcomes or so. Problems have been categorized to majorly three different categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple Problems
Complicated Problems
Complex Problems
Simple Problems are real simple problems. We can solve them following some particular method or set of steps. For examples Riding a Bike, making a cup of tea, baking your favourite cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these come under simple problems. To solve you don’t have to go deep, no need of brainstorming. With some steps to follow, you’re able to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then comes complicated problems. Complicated problems are hard, but can be broken down further to solve. For example, putting a satellite into orbit. Sending a human being on a space mission. All these are example of complicated problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some real good science knowledge, may be astrophysics and some billionaire sponsor you can achieve your target. So complicated problems can be broken down further to simple problems and each can be solved on their own. And Woah! You solved a complicated, impossible looking problem. You know Everything is hard, before its easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third category is complex problems. Not sure If these are hard, but surely serious problems! Can you see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about this. Raising a kid is an example of a complex problem. There’s no solution cookbook. No defined steps for that. Every kid is different in his/her own way. It’s impossible to treat everyone the same way. That’s complex isn’t it? Then what’s the way to solve these life problems? Is there any hack to these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be that day wasn’t a great day. I wanted an answer but that was not the solution to my problem. Well neither got the answer (expected) nor the solution. Came back home, I thought about it. I was able to convince myself that I need time and It’ll be okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that it? over? Really? No!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution to Complex problems can’t be that easy. If I don’t know what are the steps, how am I supposed to solve a problem. Then comes the saviour with a life hack. That is time. In my experience there’s some mathematics going on in the background, may be that looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hack to complex problem = time / (efforts \* (patience + believe))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more efforts you put, more the chances of feeling less complexity. If you put zero efforts or don’t show any patience or believe, then, guess what? Complexity can be infinity. As it happened in my case. Then there is time. If somehow you put good amount of efforts and patience, you believe that It’ll be okay, then It’s the moment you’ve hacked your problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And If you’re really good at maths and think, what If we put time = 0. Problem will be zero. Then you’re absolutely right. It’ll be zero. But that’s called a straight life line. We’ve a quote for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is the solution to all Problems. No man – no Problems. ~ Joseph Stalin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
