<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>execuse | Vikash Sharma</title>
    <link>/tag/execuse/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/execuse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>execuse</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 18:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>execuse</title>
      <link>/tag/execuse/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear: Sister of an Excuse</title>
      <link>/post/fear-sister-of-an-excuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 18:47:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/fear-sister-of-an-excuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It felt so good, when I noticed two things I was very good at. First was giving up and second was the fear of doing things. And then a sudden wink (a not that creepy one), I thought why not combine these two. I gave up on fear of doing the things I wanted. May be that’s why I’m writing funny and boring stuff today. And really, this so called fear is stopping a majority of gentlemen and ladies from what they really want to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a coincidence but I know a guy, who once worked as a salesman. His job was to visit houses door to door and sell stuff, the kind of stuff people restrain to buy. And he was so confident with his fear that he will never be able to make it through. How can you sell stuff, if even you’re not confident about it? He was so used to the negative response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was stunned recently to see a big change in him. I was eager to know what exactly changed him and his answer really changed my perspective (may be because I was able to see the results). His exact words were “I kept trying to sell the stuff, and when I got my first customer, there was no going back. It was me who was wrong and not the product. Once I believed that it works, I was able to sell.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to keep doing it. And when you break through it, it really becomes a game for you. Fear shouldn’t be a reason, why you’re not able to achieve something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure death can make it to the top five reasons to fear. And we all know smoking cigarettes kill people. Yet study shows that 70% of people who know this deep inside their heart do not stop smoking. Jokes apart, but I believe fear is nothing but an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the times, we act like this gentleman up against the wall on the right and do something when there’s nowhere to go. But in that we lose the flexibility to plan upfront and deliver well. It’s now obvious that we’ve have to practice so that we don’t use fear as an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a need of deliberate practice, not just physical practice, but mental practice. If you’ve something in your mind that’s not letting you try out things that you want to, it’s your duty to find a way or if it does not exist, make a way and then put massive action to accomplish. If you really think fear is even a word, then you use it your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A famous writer, wrote in his book, if an emotional hook named fear is stopping you to try out your stuff, take yourself out of the motion picture of your life and imagine you’re watching yourself in the frame. Now, think like an 8-year-old, free yourself from “what others may think of me”, “what if they don’t like my work” or “What if I fail” and remember Nike’s slogan (not too much for an 8-year-old, right?), just do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time try at least once, before you talk yourself out. And come ‘on give up on Fear!
End title: Another boring post[five]: Fear {lol, don&amp;rsquo;t buy it!}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
